<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom=".. xmlns:dc="..
  <channel>
    <title>About the Formal Proposal category</title>
    <link>..
    <description>Once a signal proposal has received 5 likes to indicate that it has a level of support within the community, it can be posted as a formal proposal. 

The formal proposal should be a detailed write up of the signal proposal that has gained support, and be identified by the same number.  An example is given in *SUDAO-IP 0: Example proposal.*  If two or more different proposals are made from the same signal check, these should be indicated by versioning number.  Examples are given in SUDAO-IP 0.1: Example proposal and Example proposal 0.2.

 This proposal should include a poll with three elements
 - Yes
 - More Discussion
 - No

In order for a proposal to pass to a Snapshot vote a simple majority (51% of votes cast) is required for Yes. In order for this vote to be valid there is a quorum of 10% SuperUMAns and 3 UMAsters, with the poll running for a maximum of 7 days.  If at the end of 7 days the quorum is not met, or there is no majority, the proposal will fail. 

Formal proposals will be announced on a Discord announcements channel</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 12:45:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Formal Proposal</category>
    <atom:link href=".. rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>About the Formal Proposal category</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[mhairi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Once a signal proposal has received 5 likes to indicate that it has a level of support within the community, it can be posted as a formal proposal.</p>
<p>The formal proposal should be a detailed write up of the signal proposal that has gained support, and be identified by the same number.  An example is given in <em>SUDAO-IP 0: Example proposal.</em>  If two or more different proposals are made from the same signal check, these should be indicated by versioning number.  Examples are given in SUDAO-IP 0.1: Example proposal and Example proposal 0.2.</p>
<p>This proposal should include a poll with three elements</p>
<ul>
<li>Yes</li>
<li>More Discussion</li>
<li>No</li>
</ul>
<p>In order for a proposal to pass to a Snapshot vote a simple majority (51% of votes cast) is required for Yes. In order for this vote to be valid there is a quorum of 10% SuperUMAns and 3 UMAsters, with the poll running for a maximum of 7 days.  If at the end of 7 days the quorum is not met, or there is no majority, the proposal will fail.</p>
<p>Formal proposals will be announced on a Discord announcements channel</p>
          <p><a href=".. full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>..
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 14:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discourse.superumans.xyz-post-15-1</guid>
        <source url=".. the Formal Proposal category</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
