<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom=".. xmlns:dc="..
  <channel>
    <title>SUDAO-IP-16: Team Lead Nomination Process [Passed but being reworked]</title>
    <link>..
    <description>**SUDAO-IP-16**

**Team Lead Nomination Process**

**Rationale:**

There is a need for guidance in determining a process for replacing team leads that either no longer wish to be a team lead or take a leave of absence. This will assist for whether the team lead takes a short leave or needs to be fully replaced.

**Content of the proposal:**

* To be a team lead one must be a UMAster or Core SuperUMAn.
* If a team lead is not performing their duties or is absent for at least a month, the team lead nomination process will begin.
* If a team lead isn&#39;t performing their duties then there must be reasoning behind the call for a new team lead vote to take place. The reasoning will be submitted along with a discord poll that needs 51% majority of SuperUMAns to support in order for the team lead nomination process to begin.
* Create a role called sub-team lead. Each team will be required to have at least 1-2 sub-team lead(s) who will assist the team lead directly. If a team lead needs to take a short leave of absence or will miss team meetings then the sub-team lead will fill in. The sub-team lead(s) ultimate goal is to keep the team moving forward when the team lead is unavailable. Leading calls, continuing to work on their team&#39;s goals, providing guidance, etc. It will be up to each team to decide who the sub team lead(s) will be.
* At the end of each quarter there is to be a team lead nomination process for all teams.
* The team lead nomination process will be held for 5 days. A UMAster or Core SuperUMAn may either self nominate or be nominated by another SuperUMAn. If nominated by another SuperUMAn there must be acknowledgement by either reacting to the nomination or replying to accept the nomination. After 5 days a 24/48 hour discord poll will be put up by the operations team. The nominations with the most SuperUMAn votes will become team leads. In the event of a tie another poll will be put up with the tied nominees
* It will be documented on notion and discord as to who are the current team and sub-team lead(s).

**Reasoning:**

* Team leads can be either Core Superumans or UMAsters because there might not actually be a qualified or interested UMAster to take over as team lead thus giving us a larger pool to work with.
* There will be times when a team lead goes AWOL or just isn&#39;t really meeting the needs of a team and a new team leads process will need to begin right away. If gone for too long the team leads process should begin ASAP. If not meeting the teams needs there will need to be reasoning to back up this claim and approval by the DAO for a team leads nomination process for that specific team to begin.
* Sub team leads will play a major role in the overall team structure as the ones to step in when the team leads won&#39;t be available. We&#39;re facing some serious issues where a team lead goes absent and then a team&#39;s functions/momentum starts to see a rapid decline.
* The end of quarter team leads nomination process is important because ultimately a team lead might want to step down, another team member might be seen as a better fit, and overall it just guarantees we are currently putting the best possible members in these positions each quarter.

**Changes to [SuperUMAn DAO - Design Principles V2 - Google Docs](..

**Under structure of the SuperUMAn DAO after preamble.**

A team lead can be either an UMAster or a Core SuperUMAn.The process will be done at the end of each quarter or when a team lead is not performing their duties with a reasoning behind the call for a new team lead.The reasoning will be submitted along with a discord poll that needs 51% majority of SuperUMAns to support in order for the team lead nomination process to begin. 

There’ll be a new role called sub team lead whose goal is to keep the team moving forward when the team lead is unavailable. Leading calls, continuing to work on their team&#39;s goals, providing guidance, etc. The sub team lead will be chosen by the team leads. The nomination process will be held for 5 days. An UMAster or Core SuperUMAn may either self nominate or be nominated by another SuperUMAn. 

If nominated by another SuperUMAn there must be acknowledgement by either reacting to the nomination or replying to accept the nomination. After 5 days a 24/48 hour discord poll will be put up by the operations team. The nominations with the most SuperUMAn votes will become team leads. In the event of a tie another poll will be put up with the tied nominees.

**What on-chain actions might this proposal entail:**

none at this time</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 18:49:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Signal</category>
    <atom:link href=".. rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>SUDAO-IP-16: Team Lead Nomination Process [Passed but being reworked]</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[FruityCup]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            
          <p><a href=".. full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>..
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 13:35:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discourse.superumans.xyz-post-1346-11</guid>
        <source url=".. Team Lead Nomination Process [Passed but being reworked]</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>SUDAO-IP-16: Team Lead Nomination Process [Passed but being reworked]</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[rhorse]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Don’t agree with a team lead structure. It has its good points but feels like over-administration.  Self-reporting and bounties would be more DAOish.</p>
          <p><a href=".. full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>..
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 18:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discourse.superumans.xyz-post-1346-10</guid>
        <source url=".. Team Lead Nomination Process [Passed but being reworked]</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>SUDAO-IP-16: Team Lead Nomination Process [Passed but being reworked]</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Deadcoin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote group-Umasters" data-username="Ponmile" data-post="1" data-topic="1346">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img loading="lazy" alt="" width="20" height="20" src=".. class="avatar"> Ponmile:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>If a team lead isn’t performing their duties then there must be reasoning behind the call for a new team lead vote to take place. The reasoning will be submitted along with a discord poll that needs 51% majority of SuperUMAns to support in order for the team lead nomination process to begin.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I have concern here that 51% of SuperUMAns do not know enough about a particular team to sufficiently be able to determine what is best for the team in question. I can see this as the same issues we will face and were brought up with Coordinape yesterday. This has a potential of becoming a popularity contest for who has the most friends and not based on true merit or what is best for the team. Thus creating numerous problems in the numerous possible situations.<br>
I will end this with just one example of the many possible outcomes:</p>
<p>If a Lead is not fulfilling expectations or obligations and a poll was put up and supported by all 10 team members, why should their vote be overridden by other SuperUMAns with less knowledge of anything going on on that team?</p>
<ul>
<li>Destroying any incentive to remain on that team.</li>
<li>Members are forced to remain dealing with whatever the problem was in the first place.</li>
<li>Added fuel to the fire is the fact that everyone on the team has made it clear in a <em><strong>transparent</strong></em> vote that they do not want this person to lead them.</li>
<li>This downward spiral will cause animosity between the Lead and team members and a good chance that this will become a toxic environment. In creating this unhealthy environment, we could see some bad situations arise that could have and should have been avoided.<br>
Who are we to force a team to deal with a unwanted leader?</li>
</ul>
          <p><a href=".. full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>..
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 14:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discourse.superumans.xyz-post-1346-9</guid>
        <source url=".. Team Lead Nomination Process [Passed but being reworked]</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>SUDAO-IP-16: Team Lead Nomination Process [Passed but being reworked]</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Ponmile]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I think it’s necessary to ensure the people that have the team leads have the DAOs backing every quarter. There could be others that wish to be a team lead and without some opportunity may never have a chance to at least have a vote.</p>
          <p><a href=".. full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>..
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 11:24:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discourse.superumans.xyz-post-1346-8</guid>
        <source url=".. Team Lead Nomination Process [Passed but being reworked]</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>SUDAO-IP-16: Team Lead Nomination Process [Passed but being reworked]</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Ponmile]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This could be open for more discussion though I’d lean more on it being just UMAsters and Core SuperUMAns as they are more trusted cos they spend more time in the DAO.</p>
          <p><a href=".. full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>..
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 11:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discourse.superumans.xyz-post-1346-7</guid>
        <source url=".. Team Lead Nomination Process [Passed but being reworked]</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>SUDAO-IP-16: Team Lead Nomination Process [Passed but being reworked]</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Bananachain_Nanner]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I understand  the rational why team leads are suppose to be Core or Masters. Though one could open this up by saying any SuperUMAn, as long as sponsored by a sufficient amount of Core/Masters. Isn’t it that we have a lack of team leads currently? One can differentiate more between status and function thus being more flexible.</p>
          <p><a href=".. full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>..
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 09:31:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discourse.superumans.xyz-post-1346-6</guid>
        <source url=".. Team Lead Nomination Process [Passed but being reworked]</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>SUDAO-IP-16: Team Lead Nomination Process [Passed but being reworked]</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Victorfela]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi Ponmile,</p>
<p>As highlighted you’re saying the team lead nomination process can be activated whenever a need arise.</p>
<p>Then circling back to this here, is it necessary to have a quarterly nomination process, since the process can be activated anytime a team lead wants to step down or there is inactivity.</p>
<aside class="quote group-Umasters" data-username="Ponmile" data-post="1" data-topic="1346">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img loading="lazy" alt="" width="20" height="20" src=".. class="avatar"> Ponmile:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>The end of quarter team leads nomination process is important because ultimately a team lead might want to step down, another team member might be seen as a better fit, and overall it just guarantees we are currently putting the best possible members in these positions each quarter.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I’m a bit hesitant with this process here as it might not have a good outlook and could affect positions, likewise having members charged to adjusting to a new lead every epoch, unless the quarterly nomination process only gets activated if a current lead wants to step down? And if yes, then no comment.</p>
          <p><a href=".. full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>..
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 08:13:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discourse.superumans.xyz-post-1346-5</guid>
        <source url=".. Team Lead Nomination Process [Passed but being reworked]</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>SUDAO-IP-16: Team Lead Nomination Process [Passed but being reworked]</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Ponmile]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi Arcology, these are really good questions. Tasks like leading calls, working on team goals, providing guidance and being the go to person of the team among other things are what a team lead does. Failure to do these classifies you as an inactive team lead.<br>
I’ll add this to the proposal before it moves to the next phase.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What if there is none? Who is eligible to be a deputy lead?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Only UMAsters and Core SuperUMAns are eligible to be sub team leads, will also add this to the proposal.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What happens if the team lead exits/drops sometime in the middle of an epoch? I’d think that a replacement needs to be found immediately/urgently rather than wait for the end of an epoch.<br>
Also, what happens if there are no takers for a team lead role? Would someone need to be an acting lead? And for how long?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>If the team lead drops in the middle of an epoch, the process will start immediately. It is encouraged that there be 1 or 2 deputies so they can act in the absence of the team lead till they are back.</p>
          <p><a href=".. full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>..
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discourse.superumans.xyz-post-1346-4</guid>
        <source url=".. Team Lead Nomination Process [Passed but being reworked]</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>SUDAO-IP-16: Team Lead Nomination Process [Passed but being reworked]</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Heruvim78]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>the idea of having 2 assistants at least is good, as they can learn what to do in case they are needed to help. even a mentoring relationship could be beneficial to the dao, when they can learn from the lead. also, we need to have some emergency procedures in place, if a team lead is leaving or it is unavailable.</p>
          <p><a href=".. full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>..
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 15:28:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discourse.superumans.xyz-post-1346-3</guid>
        <source url=".. Team Lead Nomination Process [Passed but being reworked]</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>SUDAO-IP-16: Team Lead Nomination Process [Passed but being reworked]</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[arcology]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote group-Umasters" data-username="Ponmile" data-post="1" data-topic="1346">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img loading="lazy" alt="" width="20" height="20" src=".. class="avatar"> Ponmile:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>If a team lead is not performing their duties or is absent for at least a month, the team lead nomination process will begin.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>How do you quantify that a team lead is not doing his/her duties, and what is the standard that we should be defining here?</p>
<aside class="quote group-Umasters" data-username="Ponmile" data-post="1" data-topic="1346">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img loading="lazy" alt="" width="20" height="20" src=".. class="avatar"> Ponmile:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Each team will be required to have at least 1-2 sub-team lead(s) who will assist the team lead directly.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>What if there is none? Who is eligible to be a deputy lead?</p>
<aside class="quote group-Umasters" data-username="Ponmile" data-post="1" data-topic="1346">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img loading="lazy" alt="" width="20" height="20" src=".. class="avatar"> Ponmile:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>At the end of each quarter there is to be a team lead nomination process for all teams.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>What happens if the team lead exits/drops sometime in the middle of an epoch? I’d think that a replacement needs to be found immediately/urgently rather than wait for the end of an epoch.</p>
<p>Also, what happens if there are no takers for a team lead role? Would someone need to be an acting lead? And for how long?</p>
          <p><a href=".. full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>..
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 14:32:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discourse.superumans.xyz-post-1346-2</guid>
        <source url=".. Team Lead Nomination Process [Passed but being reworked]</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>SUDAO-IP-16: Team Lead Nomination Process [Passed but being reworked]</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Ponmile]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><strong>SUDAO-IP-16</strong></p>
<p><strong>Team Lead Nomination Process</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rationale:</strong></p>
<p>There is a need for guidance in determining a process for replacing team leads that either no longer wish to be a team lead or take a leave of absence. This will assist for whether the team lead takes a short leave or needs to be fully replaced.</p>
<p><strong>Content of the proposal:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>To be a team lead one must be a UMAster or Core SuperUMAn.</li>
<li>If a team lead is not performing their duties or is absent for at least a month, the team lead nomination process will begin.</li>
<li>If a team lead isn’t performing their duties then there must be reasoning behind the call for a new team lead vote to take place. The reasoning will be submitted along with a discord poll that needs 51% majority of SuperUMAns to support in order for the team lead nomination process to begin.</li>
<li>Create a role called sub-team lead. Each team will be required to have at least 1-2 sub-team lead(s) who will assist the team lead directly. If a team lead needs to take a short leave of absence or will miss team meetings then the sub-team lead will fill in. The sub-team lead(s) ultimate goal is to keep the team moving forward when the team lead is unavailable. Leading calls, continuing to work on their team’s goals, providing guidance, etc. It will be up to each team to decide who the sub team lead(s) will be.</li>
<li>At the end of each quarter there is to be a team lead nomination process for all teams.</li>
<li>The team lead nomination process will be held for 5 days. A UMAster or Core SuperUMAn may either self nominate or be nominated by another SuperUMAn. If nominated by another SuperUMAn there must be acknowledgement by either reacting to the nomination or replying to accept the nomination. After 5 days a 24/48 hour discord poll will be put up by the operations team. The nominations with the most SuperUMAn votes will become team leads. In the event of a tie another poll will be put up with the tied nominees</li>
<li>It will be documented on notion and discord as to who are the current team and sub-team lead(s).</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Reasoning:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Team leads can be either Core Superumans or UMAsters because there might not actually be a qualified or interested UMAster to take over as team lead thus giving us a larger pool to work with.</li>
<li>There will be times when a team lead goes AWOL or just isn’t really meeting the needs of a team and a new team leads process will need to begin right away. If gone for too long the team leads process should begin ASAP. If not meeting the teams needs there will need to be reasoning to back up this claim and approval by the DAO for a team leads nomination process for that specific team to begin.</li>
<li>Sub team leads will play a major role in the overall team structure as the ones to step in when the team leads won’t be available. We’re facing some serious issues where a team lead goes absent and then a team’s functions/momentum starts to see a rapid decline.</li>
<li>The end of quarter team leads nomination process is important because ultimately a team lead might want to step down, another team member might be seen as a better fit, and overall it just guarantees we are currently putting the best possible members in these positions each quarter.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Changes to <a href=".. rel="noopener nofollow ugc">SuperUMAn DAO - Design Principles V2 - Google Docs</a></strong></p>
<p><strong>Under structure of the SuperUMAn DAO after preamble.</strong></p>
<p>A team lead can be either an UMAster or a Core SuperUMAn.The process will be done at the end of each quarter or when a team lead is not performing their duties with a reasoning behind the call for a new team lead.The reasoning will be submitted along with a discord poll that needs 51% majority of SuperUMAns to support in order for the team lead nomination process to begin.</p>
<p>There’ll be a new role called sub team lead whose goal is to keep the team moving forward when the team lead is unavailable. Leading calls, continuing to work on their team’s goals, providing guidance, etc. The sub team lead will be chosen by the team leads. The nomination process will be held for 5 days. An UMAster or Core SuperUMAn may either self nominate or be nominated by another SuperUMAn.</p>
<p>If nominated by another SuperUMAn there must be acknowledgement by either reacting to the nomination or replying to accept the nomination. After 5 days a 24/48 hour discord poll will be put up by the operations team. The nominations with the most SuperUMAn votes will become team leads. In the event of a tie another poll will be put up with the tied nominees.</p>
<p><strong>What on-chain actions might this proposal entail:</strong></p>
<p>none at this time</p>
          <p><a href=".. full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>..
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 13:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discourse.superumans.xyz-post-1346-1</guid>
        <source url=".. Team Lead Nomination Process [Passed but being reworked]</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
